(水蜡树街)
I should've known that you would be here
我早该料到你也会来
Professor McGonagall.
麦格教授
Good evening, Professor Dumbledore.
邓布利多教授
Are the rumors true, Albus?
那些传言是真的.阿不思？
I'm afraid so, professor.
恐怕是真的.教授
The good and the bad.
有好消息也有坏消息
And the boy?
那孩子呢？
Hagrid is bringing him.
海格会带来的
Is it wise to trust Hagrid with something so important?
把这么重要的事托付给海格办这是不是明智？
Professor, I would trust Hagrid with my life.
哎.教授.我能把性命托付给海格
Professor Dumbledore, sir.
邓布利多教授
Professor McGonagall.
麦格教授
No problems, I trust, Hagrid?
没遇到什么麻烦吧.海格？
No, sir.
没有.先生
Little tyke fell asleep as we were flying over Bristol.
我们飞过布里斯托的时候小傢伙就睡着了
Try not to wake him.
可别吵醒他
There you go.
给你
Do you really think it's safe,leaving him with these people?
阿不思.把孩子交给这家人你真觉得安全吗？
I've watched them all day.
我观察了他们一整天
They're the worst sort of Muggles.
没见过比他们更糟糕的麻瓜啦
- They really are... - The only family he has.
- 他们真是… - 是这孩子唯一的亲人
He'll be famous
这孩子会出名
Every child in our world will know his name
我们世界里的孩子都会知道他的名字
Exactly.
说得正是
He's far better off growing up away from all of that.
他成长时候得让他远离那些事
Until he's ready.
直到他懂事以后
There, there, Hagrid.
好了.好了.海格
It's not really goodbye, after all.
这毕竟不是真正的告别
(德思礼夫妇敬启 萨里郡小惠金区女贞路四号)
Good luck...
祝福你
...Harry Potter.
哈利·波特
《哈利波特与魔法石》
Up. Get up!
起床！快起床！
Now!
快！
Wake up, cousin! We're going to the zoo!
醒醒.表弟！要去动物园啦
Here he comes, the birthday boy.
喔.你来了.我们的小寿星
Happy birthday, son.
生日快乐.儿子
Cook breakfast.And try not to burn anything.
你给我乖乖地做早饭.别再把东西烤糊了
Yes, Aunt Petunia.
好.佩妮阿姨
I want everything to be perfect...
我希望今天样样事情都顺顺当当的
...for my Dudley's special day!
我们的小达力今天过生日
Hurry up!
快点！
Bring my coffee, boy.
拿咖啡来.小子
Yes, Uncle Vernon.
是.弗农姨丈
Aren't they wonderful, darling?
瞧这些礼物多棒.宝贝儿？
How many are there?
一共多少件？
36. Counted them myself.
三十六件.我亲自数过
36?! But last year I had 37!
只有三十六件？就在去年我还有三十七件呐
But some are bigger than last year's.
对..对..可是今年有些礼物要比去年大
I don't care!
我不管它们有有多大！
This is what we're going to do.
好了.好了.那么这样吧我们一会儿出去
We're going to buy you two new presents. How's that, pumpkin?
再给你买两个新礼物怎么样.心肝？
It should be a lovely day at the zoo.
我们一会儿就能到,今天这天气去动物园真是美极了
I'm really looking forward to it.
我想一定棒.看着吧
I'm warning you now, boy.
我现在警告你.小子
Any funny business, any at all...
要是耍什么花招.哪怕就一次
...and you won't have any meals for a week.
我就罚你一星期不准吃饭
Get in.
上车
（爬虫类馆）
Make it move.
快叫它动
Move!
动！
- Move! - He's asleep!
- 动！ - 它在睡觉
He's boring.
真没劲
Sorry about him.He doesn't understand what it's like,
真对不起.他从没尝过那种滋味
lying there...
一天一天地躺在那儿
...watching people press their ugly faces in on you.
面对凑过来看你的那些丑八怪
Can you hear me?
你能听见我的话？
It's just,
只是我…
I've never taliked to a snake before.
我从来没跟蛇说过话
Do you?
你是…
Do you talk to people often?
我是说.你经常跟人说话？
You're from Burma,
你是从缅甸来的？
aren't you? Was it nice there? Do you miss your family?
那儿不错？你想家吗？
（园内孵育样本）
I see.
懂了
That's me as well. I never knew my parents either.
我们一样.我也从没见过父母
Mummy, Dad, you won't believe
妈妈！爸爸！快来！
what this snake is doing!
瞧这蛇.这太神了
Thanks.
谢谢
Anytime.
别客气
Snake!
蛇！
Mum! Mummy! Help me!
妈妈.妈妈.快来救我
My darling boy! How did you get in there?
宝贝儿子.你是怎 么进去的？
Who did this? How did you get in there?
我的天哪.你是怎么进去的？
Is there a snake?
里面有蛇？里面有蛇？
It's all right, sweetheart.
没事.亲爱的.没事的
We'll get you out of these cold clothes.
快把你的衣服脱下来.又冷又湿的
What happened?
是怎么回事？
I swear, I don't know!
我发誓我不知道
The glass was there and then it was gone,
刚才玻璃还在.可一下就没了
like magic.
就像魔法
There's no such thing as magic.
这世上根本就没有什么魔法
Vernon, look at him! l can't believe it!
噢.发现了吗？快看看他.我简直不能相信
ln a week, he'll be off to Smeltings.！
只有我们才配上SMELTlNG（中学）
Caveat Smeltonia. Proudest moment of my life.
儿子.这是我一生最骄傲的一刻！
Will l have to wear that too?
我也得穿这身校服吗？
What? Go to Smeltings?
你？去SMELTlNG中学？
Don't be stupid! You're going to the state school.
别犯傻了！你只能去你所属的学校
This is what you'll wear when l finish dyeing it.
这就是你要穿的衣服.快染好了！
That's Dudley's old uniform. lt'll fit like old elephant skin.
但那是德利的旧校服.穿起来和大象皮差不多…
Fit you well enough.Go get the post. Go!
你穿再合适不过了！去拿邮件！去！
(女贞路四号 楼梯下的碗橱 哈利·波特先生收)
Marge is ill. Ate a funny whelk.
喔.玛姬病了.因为吃了坏油螺
Dad, look! Harry's got a letter!
爸.瞧！哈利收到一封信
It's mine!
还给我！是我的
Yours? Who'd be writing to you?
你的？谁会给你写信？
No more mail through this letterbox.
这信箱里今后再也不会有信了
Have a lovely day at the office, dear.
我爱你
Shoo! Go on.
滚.滚开
Fine day, Sunday.
好日子.星期天
In my opinion, best day of the week.
一星期中最好的一天
Why is that, Dudley?
为什么.达力？
Because there's no post on Sundays?
因为星期天没有邮差？
Right you are, Harry!
说得对.哈利
No post on Sunday.
星期天没邮差.哈哈
No blasted letters today! No, sir.
今天没有那些该死的信！没有信！
Not one single bloody letter. Not one!
今天连一封该死的信都没有.没有
No, sir, not one blasted, miserable...
一封都没有.没有一封可恶的.该死的…
Make it stop, please!
嘿.快走开
Stop it!
停！快停！
Mummy, what's happening?
妈妈.告诉我 这是怎么一回事？
Give me that!
快给我
Give me that letter!
快把信给我
Get off!
快住手！
They're my letters! Let go of me!
这些信是我的.快放开我！
That's it! We're going away!
快走吧.我们快走
Far away, where they can't find us!
搬得远远的.让他们找不到我们
Daddy's gone mad, hasn't he?
爸爸是不是发疯了？
（哈利 生日快乐）
Make a wish, Harry.
许个愿.哈利
Who's there?
是谁呀？
Sorry about that.
真是对不起啦
I demand that you leave at once.
我要你马上离开.先生
You are breaking and entering.
你私闯民宅
Dry up, Dursley, you great prune.
闭嘴.德思礼.你这个老无赖
I haven't seen you since you was a baby,
上次见到你.你还是个小宝宝
Harry.
哈利…
You're a bit more along than I expected.
可你比我想象要大一圈
Particularly in the middle.
尤其是当中这块
I'm not Harry.
我不是.我不是哈利
I am.
我.我是
Well, of course you are.
你不是就没人是啦
Got something for you.
我有东西给你
Afraid I sat on it, but
恐怕被我的屁股压坏了一点 不过…
I imagine it'll taste fine just the same.
我想味还是一样鲜美
Baked it myself, words and all.
我自己做的.字也是我写的
（祝哈利生日快乐）
Thank you.
谢谢
It's not every day your young man turns 11, is it?
小伙子可不是天天过十一岁生日的
Excuse me,
对不起.请问…
but who are you?
你是谁？
Rubeus Hagrid, Keeper of Keys
我叫鲁伯·海格 霍格沃茨的钥匙保管员…
and Grounds at Hogwarts.
场地看守人
Of course, you know about Hogwarts.
当然霍格沃茨的事你都知道
Sorry, no.
对不起.不知道
Didn't you ever wonder where your mum and dad learned it all?
不知道？你就没想过你爸爸妈妈是在哪儿学的？
Learned what?
学什么？
You're a wizard, Harry.
你是魔法师.哈利
I'm a what?
我…我是什么？
A wizard.A good one, I'd wager,once you're trained up.
魔法师.而且可以成为最最棒的只要开导开导
No
不
you've made a mistake. I mean...
你一定是弄错了
...I can't be a wizard.
我…,不可能是魔法师
I mean, I'm just
我只是…只是…
Harry. Just Harry.
哈利.只是哈利
Well, Just Harry,
好吧.只是哈利
did you ever make anything happen?
你激动的时候
Anything you couldn't explain, when you were angry or scared?
有没有做过连你自己都没法解释的事？
"Dear Mr. Potter,
亲爱的波特先生
We are pleased to accept you...
我们很高兴地通知你
...at Hogwarts School of Witchcraft and Wizardry."
你已经被我们霍格沃茨魔法学校录取了
He will not be going!
告诉你吧.他不会去的
We swore
我们发过誓
we'd put a stop to all this rubbish.
不要让他跟那些垃圾沾边
You knew?
你们知道？
You knew all along and you never told me?
你们早知道.可就是不告诉我？
Of course we knew.
当然知道
How could you not be?
怎么可能不知道
My perfect sister being who she was.
我那妹妹居然有那种本事
My mother and father were so proud the day she got her letter.
在她收到信的那一天我的父母是多么的自豪
"We have a witch in the family.Isn't it wonderful?"
我们家出了个魔法师.太妙了
I was the only one to see her for what she was.
只有我知道她是什么货色.她…
A freak!
是一个…怪胎
Then she met that Potter,and then she had you...
后来他和波特一起生下了你
...and I knew you would be the same.
我料到你们会一个样…
Just as strange, just as abnormal.
你跟他一样怪.跟他一样不正常
And then she got herself blown up,
后来你妈让她自己给炸死了
and we got landed with you.
我们只能把你收下
Blown up? You told me my parents died in a car crash.
给炸死？ 你们不是说我的父母是车祸死的吗？
A car crash?
车祸死的？
A car crash killed Lily and James Potter?
车祸能让莉莉和和詹姆斯送命？
We had to say something.
总得编点什么呀
It's an outrage! A scandal!
简直是侮辱他们.天大的耻辱
He'll not be going.
他不会去的
A great Muggle like you is going to stop him?
喔…难道像你这样一个麻瓜能阻止得了他吗？
Muggle?
麻瓜？
Non-magic folk.
不懂魔法的人
This boy's had his name down since he were born.
这孩子自打一出生就注册了
He's going to the finest school of witchcraft and wizardry.
他要去的是世界上最好的魔法学校
He'll be under the finest headmaster Hogwarts has seen,
而且现在的校长是霍格沃茨魔法学校历史上最棒的
Albus Dumbledore.
阿不思邓布利多
I will not pay to have a crackpot old fool teach him magic tricks.
我可不会出钱让一个老疯子老傻瓜教这小子变戏法
Never insult Albus Dumbledore...in front of me.
不许…在我面前侮辱阿不思邓布利多.绝对不允许
What did they do to my baby?
他们对我的小宝贝做了什么？
I'd appreciate it if you didn't tell anyone at Hogwarts about that.
这事你最好别告诉霍格沃茨的人
I'm not allowed to do magic.
因为他们不允许我施魔法
Okay.
好的
We're a bit behind schedule. Best be off.
噢！时间不早了.我们得走了
Unless you'd rather stay, of course.
当然.除非你宁愿留下
''First years will require three sets of work robes...
（魔法学校）一年级新生需要准备…三件素色巫衣…
...one wand.''
一根魔杖？
Essential bit of equipment, Harry.
一件尤为关键的装备.哈利
''One pair of dragon hide gloves.''
一双龙皮手套…
Do they mean from a real dragon?
海格.是取自真龙身上吗？
They don't mean a penguin, do they?
这个嘛.他们肯定指的不是企鹅.你说呢？
Crikey. l'd love a dragon.
噢.我要有一条龙该多好…
You'd like a dragon?
你想要一条龙！
Vastly misunderstood beasts, Harry. Vastly misunderstood.
（龙）比雷电还快.比雷电还快！
"All students must be equipped with...
所有来校学生都必须配备…
...one standard size 2 pewter cauldron...
一只标准尺寸的二号锡镴大锅
...and may bring, if they desire,
愿意的话.还可以自带…
either an owl, a cat or a toad."
一只猫头鹰.一只猫.或是一只蟾蜍
Can we find all this in London?
在伦敦能找到吗？
If you know where to go.
总能找到的
Ah, Hagrid! The usual, I presume?
啊.海格.还照老样子？
No, thanks, Tom.
不.谢谢.汤姆
I'm on official Hogwarts business.
我在为霍格沃茨办公事
Just helping Harry buy his school supplies.
我在帮小哈利买他的学习用品呐
Bless my soul.
我的天啦
It's Harry Potter!
他是哈利·波特！
Welcome back, Mr. Potter.
波特先生.欢迎回来
Welcome back.
欢迎回来
Doris Crockford.
我是科多利
I can't believe I'm meeting you at last.
真不敢相信我终于见到你了
Harry Potter.
哈利…波特
Can't tell you how pleased I am to meet you.
见到你非常兴奋
Hello, professor. I didn't see you.
你好哇.教授.刚才没看见你
Professor Quirrell will be your Defense Against the Dark Arts teacher.
哈利.这位是奇洛教授在霍格沃茨.他将教你黑魔法防御术
Oh, nice to meet you.
喔.我很荣幸
Fearfully fascinating subject.
奇妙…恐怖的学科
Not that you need it, eh, Potter?
嗯…你你并不需要它.啊？波特
Yes, well, must be going now. Lots to buy.
好吧.得走啦.我们回头见
Goodbye.
再见
See, Harry?
瞧.哈利
- You're famous. - But why am I famous?
- 你很出名 - 我为什么出名.海格？
All those people, how is it they know who I am?
那里的那些人怎么会知道我是谁？
I'm not sure I'm the right person to tell you that.
也许由我来告诉你不太合适.哈利
Welcome, Harry, to Diagon Alley.
欢迎.哈利.欢迎来对角巷
Here, you get your quills and ink.
在这儿买鹅毛笔和墨水
Over there, all your bits and bobs for doing wizardry.
哪儿有你使魔法用的各种小玩意
It's a world-class racing broom.
这是世界最著名扫帚
Look at it! The new Nimbus 2000!
哇.快看啦！那是新型的光轮2000
It's the fastest model yet.
那可是最快的型号啦
(光轮2000)
But how am I to pay for all this?
可是.海格.这些我怎么买得起呢？
I haven't any money.
我从来都没钱
There's your money.
喔.你的钱在那儿.哈利
Gringotts, the wizard bank.
古灵阁魔法师银行
Ain't no safer place, not one.
没有哪儿比那更安全了
Except perhaps Hogwarts.
除了霍格沃茨
Hagrid
海格
what exactly are these things?
这.这到底是怎么回事？
They're goblins.
他们是小妖精
Clever as they come, but not the most friendly of beasts.
他们虽然很聪明.但却并不是最友好的
Best stay close.
最好跟我近些
Mr. Harry Potter wishes to make a withdrawal.
哈利·波特先生想取一些钱
And does Mr. Harry Potter have his key?
喔…知道了 那么哈利·波特先生带钥匙来了吗？
Wait a minute. Got it here somewhere.
喔.等一下.我放哪儿啦？
Ha! There's the little devil.
哦.鬼家伙在这儿
And there's something else as well.
另外.还有一件事情
Professor Dumbledore gave me this.
邓布利多教授交给我的
（最高机密）
It's about You-Know-What in vault you-know-which.
这有关金库里藏着的那件东西
Very well.
那好吧
Vault 687.
第六百八十七号金库
Lamp, please.
把灯拿来
Key, please.
钥匙拿来
Did you think your parents would leave you with nothing?
没想过你父母会给你留下什么吧？
Vault 713.
第七百十三号金库
What's in there, Hagrid?
那里有什么.海格？
Can't tell you.
不能告诉你
Hogwarts business.
哈利.事关霍格沃茨
- Very secret. - Stand back.
- 是绝密 - 往后站
Best not to mention this to anyone.
别向任何人提这事.哈利
I still need a wand.
我还需要…一根魔杖
A wand? You want OIlivanders.
要魔杖？那就去奥利凡德
There ain't no place better.
那家店最好
Run along there and wait.
你先去那等着
I got one more thing to do. Won't be long.
我还有件事要办.就来
Hello?
哈罗？
I wondered when I'd be seeing you,
我一直在想几时能见到你
Mr. Potter.
波特先生
It seems only yesterday...
当年你父亲和母亲也在这儿
...that your mother and father were in here buying their first wands.
买他们的第一根魔杖就好象是昨天发生的事
Here we are.
给你这一根
Give it a wave.
挥一下试试
Apparently not.
这个好像不行
Perhaps...
也许是…
...this.
这根
No, no, definitely not.
不.不.绝对不是这根
No matter.
没关系
I wonder...
这根像了
Curious.
真邪乎
Very curious.
真是太邪乎了
Sorry, but what's curious?
对不起.可…你说什么邪乎？
I remember every wand I've ever sold, Mr. Potter.
我卖出的每一根魔杖我都记得
It so happens that the phoenix whose tail feather resides in your wand
碰巧的是…有两根魔杖用的羽毛出自同一只凤凰
gave another feather.
一根就是你手中的
Just one other.
另一根像它兄弟…
It is curious that you should be destined for this wand...
邪乎的是…命里注定这根魔杖为你所用
...when its brother gave you that scar.
而它的兄弟给你留下了这道疤
And who owned that wand?
谁.谁拥有那根魔杖？
We do not speak his name.
我们从不提他的名字
The wand chooses the wizard, Mr. Potter.
是魔杖选择魔法师.波特先生
It's not always clear why.
有些事就是弄不明白
But I think it is clear...
可是有一点很清楚…
...that we can expect great things from you.
那就是你一定能干出一番大事
After all, He-Who-Must-Not-Be-Named...
毕竟那个…我们不能提名字的神秘人
...did great things.
干的也是大事
Terrible...yes
很可怕.可的确…
but great.
都是大事
Harry! Harry!
哈利.哈利
Happy birthday.
生日快乐
You all right, Harry? You seem very quiet.
你没事吧？在想什么？
He killed my parents, didn't he?
他杀了我的父母.对吗？
The one who gave me this.
给我留下疤的那个人
You know, Hagrid.
你知道真相
I know you do.
你一定知道
First, and understand this because it's very important:
首先.有一点你一定要明白.因为这很重要
Not all wizards are good.
魔法师不一定都是好人
Some of them go bad.
其中有些变坏了
A few years ago...
几年前
...there was a wizard who went as bad as you can go.
有个魔法师简直坏到了极点
His name was V...
他的名字叫…
叫佛…
Maybe if you wrote it down?
你把名字写下来？
No, I can't spell it.All right,
不行.我拼不出…好吧
Voldemort.
佛地魔
Voldemort?
佛地魔？
It was dark times, Harry.
那时候真太黑暗了
Voldemort started to gather some followers.
当时佛地魔开始网罗他的党羽
Brought them over to the Dark Side.
让他们加入黑势力
Anyone that stood up to him ended up dead.
谁要跟他对抗就难逃一死
Your parents fought against him.
你的父母跟他抗上了
But nobody lived once he decided to kill them.
他要杀谁.谁就没法活
Nobody, not one.
没人能逃得了
Except you.
除了你
Me? Voldemort tried to kill me?
我？佛地魔想要杀…我？
Yes. That ain't no ordinary cut on your forehead, Harry.
是的.你额头上的疤可非同寻常.哈利
A mark like that only comes from being touched by a curse,
只有接触到魔咒才会留下那样的疤痕
an evil curse.
一种邪恶的魔咒
What happened to V... To You-Know-Who?
那么佛…他后来呢？
Well, some say he died.
喔.有人说他死了
Codswallop, in my opinion.
我看是一派胡言
Nope, I reckon he's out there still...
我想.他还活在这世上
...too tired to carry on.
精疲力尽.无法作恶
But one thing's certain.
可有一点是肯定的
Something about you stumped him that night.
那天晚上你一定挫了他的锐气
That's why you're famous.
所以你这么出名
That's why everybody knows your name.
所以大家都知道你的名字
You're the boy who lived.
你就是那…大难不死的男孩
What are you looking at?
看什么.看？
Blimey, is that the time?
我的天.时间到了？
I'm gonna have to leave you.
对不起.哈利.我得走了
Dumbledore will be wanting his...
邓布利多想要他的…
Well, he'll be wanting to see me.
他等着见我
Your train leaves in 10 minutes.
好了.火车十分钟以后开
Here's your ticket.
你的票
Stick to your ticket, that's very important.
拿好了.哈利.这非常重要.拿好你的票
（九又四分之三站台）
"Platform 93/4"?
九又四分之三站台？
But, Hagrid, there must be a mistake.
可是.海格.这一定是弄错了吧
This says platform 93/4.
上面写着九又四分之三站台
There's no such thing, is there?
没有这种站台.对吗？
Stay out of the way
别挡在门口
Sorry.
抱歉
Excuse me. Excuse me.
对不起.对不起
On your left.
穿过左边的通道.女士
Can you tell me where I might find platform 93/4?
对不起.先生请问去九又四分之三站台怎么走？
Think you're being funny, do you?
九又四分之三站台？你开玩笑吧？
It's the same every year, packed with Muggles.
年年都是这样.这到处都是麻瓜 快点
- Muggles? - Platform 93/4, this way.
- 麻瓜？ - 九又四分之三站台这边走
All right, Percy, you first.
好了.珀西.你先走
Fred, you next.
弗雷德.你跟上
He's not Fred, I am.
他不是弗雷德.我是
You call yourself our mother?
我说得了吧.你还自称是妈妈呢
I'm sorry, George.
喔.真对不起.乔治
I'm only joking. I am Fred.
闹着玩的.我是弗雷德
Excuse me.
对不起
Could you tell me how to?
请…请告诉我…怎样去…
How to get onto the platform?
怎…怎么去站台.是吗？
Not to worry, dear.
好的.别担心.宝贝儿
It's Ron's first time to Hogwarts as well.
我们家罗恩其实也是第一次去霍格沃茨
All you do is walk straight at the wall between platforms 9 and 10.
你按我说的做九和十的标牌之间的中字朝着它直接走过去
Best to run if you're nervous.
要是紧张.就一路小跑
Good luck.
祝你好运
（霍格沃茨特快车）
Excuse me.
对不起
Do you mind? Everywhere else is full.
我能坐吗？别处都坐满了
Not at all.
尽管坐吧
I'm Ron, by the way.
我叫罗恩
Ron Weasley.
罗恩·韦斯莱
I'm Harry. Harry Potter.
我叫哈利.哈利·波特
So it's true!
那么…那是真的？
I mean, do you really have the?
我是说.你真有那…那…
The what?
那什么？
The scar?
疤痕？
Wicked!
喔.绝了！
Anything off the trolley, dears?
要不要来点什么.孩子们？
No, thanks. I'm all set.
不.谢谢.我带了
We'll take the lot.
我们全要了
Bertie Bott's Every Flavor Beans?
上面写着比比多味豆？
They mean every flavor.
它有各种口味
There's chocolate and peppermint and also...
有巧克力、薄荷味的.另外还有…
...spinach, liver and tripe.
菠菜味、牛肚味、猪肝味
George sweared he got a booger-flavored one once.
乔治他还吃到过鼻涕味
Are they real frogs?
不会是真的青蛙吧？
It's a spell.
那得施魔法
You want the cards.
买它其实就是要画片
Each pack's got a famous witch or wizard.
每包都有大魔法师的画片
I've got about 500 meself.
我已经收集了五百多张了
Watch it!
它跑了
That's rotten luck.
喔.真是倒霉
They've only got one good jump in them.
它们本来只能跳一次的
I've got Dumbledore!
是邓布利多
I got about six of him.
我已经有六张了
Hey, he's gone!
呃…他不见了
You can't expect him to hang around all day, can you?
他总不见得整天都待在那儿吧.对吗？
This is Scabbers.
这是我的斑斑鼠
Pathetic, isn't he?
他很可怜吧？
A little.
有一点
Fred gave me a spell to turn him yellow. Want to see?
弗雷德教我的咒语能把它变黄.想看吗？
Yeah.
想
Has anyone seen a toad?
谁见过一只蛤蟆？
A boy named Neville's lost one.
有个叫纳威的丢了一只
No.
没有
Oh, are you doing magic?
喔.你在施魔法？
Let's see, then.
那瞧瞧吧
Sunshine, daisies, butter mellow
阳光.雏菊.黄油飘香
Turn this stupid, fat rat yellow
快快把这笨贼鼠变黄
Are you sure that's a real spell?
你肯定那真的是咒语吗？
Well, it's not very good, is it?
看来这咒语好像…不太灵？
I've only tried a few simple ones myself...
当然 我自己也试过几个简单的咒语
...but they've all worked for me.
都挺灵验的
For example:
比如说…
Oculus Reparo.
欧卡拉斯雷培洛
That's better, isn't it?
很快就修好了
Holy cricket, you're Harry Potter!
真是不得了.你是哈利·波特！
I'm Hermione Granger.
我叫赫敏·格兰杰
And you are?
那么.你是…？
I'm Ron Weasley.
我叫罗恩·韦斯莱
Pleasure.
幸会
You two better change into robes.
你们俩最好换上袍子
I expect we'll be arriving soon.
我想我们就快到了
You've got dirt on your nose. Did you know?
对了.你鼻子上有块脏东西.你知道吗？
Just there.
就在这
Right, then. First years,
我们到了.一年的的
this way, please!
请到这边.快
Come on, first years, don't be shy.
一年级的同学.别害羞
Come on now, hurry up.
快点.跟上.快
Hello, Harry.
哈罗.哈利
Hi, Hagrid.
嘿.海格
Right, then. This way to the boats.Come on now,
好了.到这边上船.快点
follow me.
跟我来
Welcome to Hogwarts.
欢迎来霍格沃茨
Shortly, you'll pass through these doors and join your classmates.
好了.再过一会儿.你们会穿过这些门和你们的同学在一起
But before you take your seats,
不过在入座以前
you must be sorted into your houses.
必须进行分类确定进哪个学院
They are Gryffindor, Hufflepuff...
有格兰芬多.赫奇帕奇
...Ravenclaw and Slytherin.
拉文克劳.和斯莱特林学院
While you're here,
在校期间
your house will be like your family.
学院就好比你们的家
Your triumphs will earn you points.
表现好能为学院加分
Any rule-breaking and you will lose points.
那个学院有人违反校规就得扣分
At the end of the year, the house with the most points wins the house cup.
到了年终的时候哪个学院的得分最高就能赢得学院杯
Trevor!
吹宝
Sorry.
对不起
The Sorting Ceremony will begin momentarily.
再过一会儿分院仪式就要开始了
It's true then,
看来刚才
what they're saying on the train.
他们说的都是真的
Harry Potter has come to Hogwarts.
哈利·波特来霍格沃茨
Harry Potter?
哈利·波特
This is Crabbe and Goyle.And I'm Malfoy.
这是克拉布.这是高尔.我叫马尔福
Draco Malfoy.
德拉科·马尔福
Think my name's funny, do you?
觉得我名字好笑吗？
I've no need to ask yours.
我不用问你叫什么
Red hair and a hand-me-down robe?
红头发.家里传下来的旧袍子
You must be a Weasley.
你一定是韦斯莱家的
You'll find out some wizarding families are better than others.
你会发现有些魔法师家族就是高人一等.波特
You don't want to go making friends with the wrong sort.
你可别跟不三不四的人交往
I can help you there.
我可以帮你
I think I can tell the wrong sort for myself, thanks.
我想我自己能分出好坏.谢谢
We're ready for you now. Follow me.
都准备好了.跟我来
The ceiling isn't real.
你瞧着这天空
It's bewitched to look like the night sky.
是天花板被施了魔法变成的
I read about it in Hogwarts, A History.
我在《霍格沃茨校史》中读到过
Will you wait along here, please?
请大家在这儿等着
Now, before we begin...
在仪式开始之前
...Professor Dumbledore would like to say a few words.
邓布利多教授要跟大家说几句话
I have a few start-of-term notices
我有几件开学注意事项
I wish to announce.
要宣布一下
The first years, please note...
一年级新生注意
...that the Dark Forest is strictly forbidden to all students.
本校严格禁止任何学生进入黑暗黑森林.那是禁令
Also, our caretaker, Mr. Filch, has asked me to remind you...
另外.我们的管理员费尔奇先生要我提醒你们
...that the third-floor corridor is out of bounds...
三楼走廊.右侧的走廊.也是禁地
...to everyone who does not wish to die a most painful death.
如果你们不想死得很惨.就千万不要去
Thank you.
谢谢
When I call your name,
叫到名字的同学
you will come forth.
就走到前面来
I shall place the Sorting Hat on your head...
我会把分院帽戴在你的头上
...and you will be sorted into your houses.
然后确定你要去的学院
Hermione Granger.
赫敏·格兰杰
Oh, no.
喔.不
Okay, relax.
好险.别紧张
Mental, that one, I'm telling you.
她脑子有病.怪怪的
Right
对了
then. Right.
嗯.没错
Okay.
好呐
Gryffindor!
格兰芬多
Draco Malfoy.
德拉科·马尔福
Slytherin!
斯莱特林
Every wizard who went bad was in Slytherin.
那些坏魔法师都是斯莱特林学院的
Susan Bones.
苏珊·博恩斯
Harry, what is it?
哈利.怎么啦？
Nothing. Nothing, I'm fine.
没什么.没什么.我没事
Let's see...
让我想想
I know!
我知道了
Hufflepuff!
赫奇帕奇
Ronald Weasley.
罗恩·韦斯莱
Another Weasley!
哈！又是一个韦斯莱
I know just what to do with you.
我知道应该把你分在哪儿
Gryffindor!
格兰芬多
Harry Potter.
哈利·波特
Difficult, very difficult.
嗯.不好办啦.这可真是太难办啦
Plenty of courage, I see. Not a bad mind, either.
看得出你很有勇气.而且心眼也不坏
There's talent, oh, yes.
才华横溢.呃.没错
And a thirst to prove yourself.
还极其渴望证明你自己
But where to put you?
可把你分在哪儿呢？
Not Slytherin, not Slytherin!
不去斯莱特林.不去斯莱特林
Not Slytherin, eh?
不去斯莱特林？
Are you sure? You could be great,
你肯定吗？你能出人头地
you know. It's all here, in your head.
智慧都在你的小脑瓜里
And Slytherin will help you on the way to greatness,
斯莱特林能帮你干成一番大事业
no doubt about that.
这一点是毫无疑问的
No? Well, if you're sure.
不去？好吧.既然你铁了心
Better be...
那就去…
...Gryffindor!
格兰芬多
Your attention, please.
请大家注意啦
Let the feast begin.
现在宴会开始
I'm half and half.
我是一半一半
Me dad's a Muggle. Mum's a witch.
我爸是麻瓜.我妈是魔法师
Bit of a nasty shock for him when he found out.
我爸发现真相后吓得够呛
Percy, who's that teacher talking to Professor Quirrell?
珀西.你瞧跟奇洛教授说话的老师是谁？
Professor Snape,
喔.那是斯内普教授
head of Slytherin house.
斯莱特林的院长
What's he teach?
他教什么？
Potions.
魔药学
But he fancies the Dark Arts.
他对黑魔法最感兴趣
He's been after Quirrell's job for years.
奇洛被他仰慕好几年了
Hello! How are you? Welcome to Gryffindor.
哈喽.你们好.欢迎来格兰芬多
It's the Bloody Baron!
看.那是血腥男爵
Hello, Sir Nicholas.
尼古拉斯爵士
Have a nice summer?
暑期愉快吗？
Dismal. Once again, my request to join the Headless Hunt has been denied.
真无聊.我申请加入无头狩猎俱乐部又被拒绝了
I know you.
原来是你
You're Nearly Headless Nick.
差点没头的尼克
I prefer Sir Nicholas, if you don't mind.
我更喜欢别人叫我尼古拉斯爵士
"Nearly" headless?
差点没头？
How can you be nearly headless?
你怎么会是差点没头？
like this.
像这样
Gryffindors, follow me, please.
格兰芬多的同学跟我来
Keep up. Thank you.
跟上.谢谢
Ravenclaw, follow me.
拉文克劳同学跟上
This way.
这边
This is the most direct path to the dormitories.
这是通往宿舍最直的一条路
Keep an eye on the staircases. They like to change.
嗯.不过得注意看楼梯.它们随时会变
Keep up, please, and follow me.
请大家跟上.跟着我
Quickly now, come on. Come on.
快.都跟上.跟上
That picture's moving.
西莫.快瞧.那幅画在动
- Look at that one. - I think she fancies you.
- 快看那幅.哈利 - 我想她是在看你
Look!
喔.看.快看！
Who's that girl?
那女的是谁？
Welcome to Hogwarts.
欢迎来霍格沃茨
Password?
通行口令？
Caput Draconis.
通行口令龙渣
Follow me, everyone.
大家跟我来
Keep up. Quickly, come on.
跟上.快点.都跟上
Gather around here.
在这儿集合
Welcome to the Gryffindor common room.
欢迎来格兰芬多公共休息室
Boys' dormitory is upstairs to the left.
男生的宿舍在楼上靠左边
Girls, the same on your right.
女生的在右边
Your belongings have already been brought up.
你们的行李物品已经送上去了
Made it!
唷.总算到了
Can you imagine the look on old McGonagall's face if we were late?
要是麦格在.她的脸色准能吓死人
That was bloody brilliant!
这手实在是太高明啦
Thank you for that assessment.
谢谢你的评价.韦斯莱先生
It'd be better if I transfigured Mr. Potter and you into a watch.
也许我该把波特先生和你变成一只怀表.那你们两个…
Then one of you might be on time.
至少有一个能遵守时间
We got lost.
我们迷路了
Then perhaps a map?
那就变成地图？
I trust you don't need one to find your seats.
上自己的座位总不要地图了吧？
There will be no foolish wand-waving or silly incantations in this class.
在我的课堂上可不许胡乱挥舞魔杖.没事乱念咒语
As such,
其实呢…
I don't expect many of you to appreciate...
我想你们不会有很多人懂得…
...the subtle science and exact art that is potion-making.
欣赏制魔药学深奥的科学和精密的工艺
However, for those select few...
然而对那些少数的、优等生…
...who possess the predisposition...
那些真正有那意向的人
...I can teach you how to bewitch the mind...
我可以教你们如何对心灵施魔法
...and ensnare the senses.
如何使感官入圈套
I can tell you how to bottle fame...
我会教你们铸造名气.酿造辉煌
...brew glory and even put a stopper in death.
甚至能教你们如何造出长生不老药
Then again,
话说回来…
maybe some of you have come to Hogwarts in possession of abilities...
也许你们有些人来霍格沃茨的时候已经具备了超凡的能力
so formidable that you feel confident enough
并且有足够的自信
...to not pay attention.
认为可以不专心听我讲课
Mr. Potter.
波特先生
Our new celebrity.
我们的一代名人
What would I get if I added root of asphodel to an infusion of wormwood?
告诉我.如果我把水仙球根粉末 加入苦艾茎液中会怎样？
You don't know?
不知道？
Let's try again.
那我问你别的
Where would you look if I asked you to find a bezoar?
波特先生.如果我要牛黄知道上哪儿找？
I don't know, sir.
不知道.老师
What is the difference between monkshood and wolfsbane?
舟形乌头和狼毒乌头有什么区别？
I don't know, sir.
不知道.老师
Pity.
可惜
Clearly, fame isn't everything...
很显然.光有名气是不够的
...is it, Mr. Potter?
对吗.波特先生？
Eye of rabbit, harp string hum
兔眼幽幽.素琴幽幽
Turn this water into rum
把这清水变为酒
Eye of rabbit...
兔眼幽幽.素琴幽幽
What's Seamus trying to do to the water?
西莫到底想把那杯水怎么样？
Turn it to rum.
变成酒
Actually managed a weak tea yesterday, before...
昨天倒是变成淡茶来 后来…
Mail's here.
啊…邮件来了
Can I borrow this? Thanks.
我借来看一下？
Thanks.
谢谢
Look, Neville's got a Remembrall.
嘿.瞧.纳威收到个记忆球
I've read about those.
我在书上读到过
The smoke turns red when you've forgotten something.
当烟变成红色就说明你忘了一件事情
The problem is,
唯一的问题是…
I can't remember what I've forgotten.
我记不起忘了什么啦
Somebody broke into Gringotts.
有人闯入古灵阁
Listen.
听这
"Believed to be the work of Dark wizards or witches...
相信是黑魔法师或者别的魔法师所为
Gringotts goblins acknowledge the breach but insist nothing was taken.
古灵阁妖精证实有人闯入但一再强调没有失窃
The vault in question, number 713,
事发现场.713号金库
had been emptied earlier that same day."
其实已于当天早些时候 被提取一空
That's odd.
奇怪
That's the vault Hagrid and I went to
那是海格和我去的金库
Good afternoon, class.
下午好.同学们
Good afternoon, Madam Hooch.
下午好.霍琦夫人
Good afternoon, Amanda. Good afternoon.
下午好.阿曼达.下午好
Welcome to your first flying lesson.
现在上第一堂飞行课
What are you waiting for?
你们还等什么？
Step up to your broomstick.
大家都站到飞天扫帚的左边
Come on now, hurry up.
好了.动作快
Stick your hand over the broom and say,
右手放到扫帚的上方.然后说
"Up."
“起来”
Up!
起来
Up.
Up. Up!
起来.起来！
With feeling.
带点感情
Shut up, Harry.
不许取笑.哈利
Now, once you've got hold of your broom,
现在.抓住你们的扫帚…
I want you to mount it.Grip it tight.
然后骑上去.紧紧抓住
You don't wanna be sliding off the end.
别滑下来啦
When I blow my whistle,
我一吹哨子.你们每个人…
I want you to kick off from the ground, hard.
都用力蹬地.腾空
Keep your broom steady, hover for a moment...
得把那扫帚扶稳了先盘旋一会
...then lean forward slightly
然后身体稍稍往前倾斜
and touch back down.
回到地面
On my whistle. Three, two...
听我的哨声…三.二…
Mr. Longbottom.
隆巴顿.你在干嘛
Mr. Longbottom! Down, down!
隆巴顿先生 下去.下去！
Neville!
纳威！
Help! Help!
救命！救命啊！
Come back down this instant!
快给我下来.听见吗
Oh! No!
喔.不！
Help!
救命啊！
Mr. Longbottom.
隆巴…
Help!
救命啊！
Everyone out of the way!
大家都让开
Is he all right?
好了.起来吧？
Oh, dear, it's a broken wrist. Poor boy.
喔.喔.老天.手腕断了
Come on now, up you get.
来.起来
Keep your feet on the ground
现在大家都老老实实地在地上呆着
while I take him to the hospital wing.
我送隆巴顿先生去医院
Understand?
懂了吗？
If I see a single broom in the air...
要是我看见天上有扫帚
...the one riding it will be expelled before they can say Quidditch.
那骑扫帚的没等说完魁地奇就给开除了
Did you see his face?
看见他的脸吗？
If he had squeezed this,
那胖墩要是捏一下这球
he'd have remembered to fall on his arse.
就会记得用屁股着地
Give it here, Malfoy.
把球给我.马尔福
No. I'll leave it somewhere for Longbottom to find.
不.我要藏起来.让纳威去找
How about on the roof?
屋顶上怎么样？
What's the matter, Potter? Bit beyond your reach?
怎么啦.波特？是不是够不着啦？
Harry, no way!
哈利.这绝对不行
You heard what Madam Hooch said.
霍琦夫人刚才说了
Besides, you don't know how to fly.
再说你还不知道怎么飞
What an idiot.
真是个大白痴
Give it here
快把他给我
or I'll knock you off your broom!
不然我就把打下去
Is that so?
口气倒不小？
Have it your way, then.
那你就瞧着办吧
Nice going, Harry.
干得好.哈利
That was wicked, Harry!
简直绝了.哈利
Harry Potter!
哈利·波特
Follow me.
跟我来
You wait here.
在这儿等着
Professor Quirrell, excuse me.
奇洛教授.对不起
Could I borrow Wood for a moment?
抱歉.我能跟伍德说几句话吗？
Yes, of course.
行行行.当然行
Potter, this is Oliver Wood.
波特.这是奥利弗·伍德
Wood, I have found you a Seeker.
伍德.我给你找了一个找球手
Have you heard?
听说了吗？
Harry Potter's the new Gryffindor Seeker.
哈利·波特是格兰芬多新的找球手
I always knew he'd do well.
我早料到他会干得很出色
Seeker?
找球手？
But first years never make the house teams.
学院队可从没收过一年级新生
You must be the youngest player in...
你一定是最年轻的球员…是百年最年轻的
A century, McGonagall says.
麦格教授说的
Well done, Harry. Wood's just told us.
嘿.棒极了.哈利 伍德跟我们说了
Fred and George are on the team.
弗雷德和乔治也在队里
Beaters.
是击球手
Our job is to make sure you don't get bloodied up too bad.
我们的任务就是…确保你不被打得七歪八斜
Can't make any promises.
但不可能没事的
Rough game, Quidditch.
魁地奇很野蛮
But no one's died in years.
很残酷.可从来没死过人
Someone vanishes occasionally.
事后偶尔有人不见了…
But they'll turn up in a month or two.
可过一、两个月又出现啦
Go on. Quidditch is great.
喔.上吧.哈利
Best game there is, and you'll be great too.
魁地奇很带劲是最刺激的 而你是最棒的
I've never played.
可我从没打过魁地奇
What if I make a fool of myself?
要是出了洋相怎么办？
You won't make a fool of yourself.
你才不会出洋相呢
It's in your blood.
有遗传天份
(找球手: 詹姆斯·波特)
You never told me your father was a Seeker too.
你从没说过你爸爸也是找球手
I didn't know.
我…我不知道
I'm telling you, it's spooky.
跟你实说吧.厉害
She knows more about you than you do.
你的事.赫敏知道的比你还多
Who doesn't?
都比我多
What's happening?
怎么回事儿？
The staircases change, remember?
这只楼梯会变.记得吗？
Let's go this way.
我们走这边
Before the staircase moves again.
不然这些楼梯又得变了
Does anybody feel like we shouldn't be here?
你们是不是觉得不该来这儿
We're not supposed to be here.
我们是不应该来这儿
This is the third floor. It's forbidden.
这是三楼.是禁止来这儿的
Let's go.
我们走
It's Filch's cat!
那是费尔奇的猫
Run!
快跑！
Quick, let's hide through that door!
快！快藏到门后去
It's locked!
门锁上了
We're done for!
完蛋.这下完了
Move over!
你给我让开
Alohomora.
[开门咒] 阿拉霍魔拉
Get in.
进去
Alohomora?
阿拉霍魔拉？
Standard Book of Spells, chapter seven.
“标准咒语”书第七章里有
Anyone here, my sweet?
有人进来了吗.亲爱的？
Come on.
走吧
Filch is gone.
费尔奇走了
He thinks this door's locked.
也许他以为没人能进来
It was locked.
门是锁着的
And for good reason.
锁上是有原因的
What are they doing,
他们这是搞什么
keeping a thing like that locked up in a school?
把那么一个怪物锁在学校里？
Didn't you see what it was standing on?
你眼睛是用来干嘛的？没看见它站在哪吗？
I wasn't looking at its feet!
我又没有看见它的脚
I was preoccupied with its heads.
我光顾着看它的那些头啦
Or maybe you didn't notice. There were three!
也许你没注意.它有三个头
It was standing on a trap door.
它站在活板门上
It wasn't there by accident.
说明不是碰巧站在那儿
It's guarding something.
它在看守东西
Guarding something?
看守东西？
That's right.
这没错
Now, if you two don't mind, I'm going to bed...
现在.要是你们俩不介意.我要去睡了
...before you come up with another idea
不然你们不知道谁又会蹦出什么妙计
to get us killed.
去送死
Or worse, expelled.
没准会更糟.被开除
She needs to sort out her priorities.
哪个更糟.她真应该想清楚再说
Quidditch is easy to understand.
魁地奇其实很容易懂
Each team has seven players.
每个队有七个队员
Three Chasers, two Beaters,
三个追球手.两个击球手
one Keeper
一个守门员
and a Seeker. That's you.
还有个找球手
There are three kinds of balls.
一共有三种球
This one's called the Quaffle.
这一种叫鬼飞球
The Chasers handle the Quaffle
追球手负责把鬼飞球
and try to put it through one of those hoops.
打进三个铁环中的一个
The Keeper, that's me, defends the hoops.
守门员就是我.守住铁环
With me so far?
懂了吗？
I think so.
咦.是这样
What are those?
那些是什么？
You better take this.
你拿好这个
Careful now, it's coming back.
小心.它回来了
Not bad, Potter.
嗯.不错嘛
You'd make a fair Beater.
你击球也不赖
What was that?
那到底是什么？
Bludger.
游走球
Nasty little buggers.
讨厌的小家伙
But you are a Seeker.
可你是…找球手
The only thing I want you to worry about is this.
你唯一要关心的是这个
The Golden Snitch.
金色飞贼
I like this ball.
我喜欢这球
Just wait.
啊.先别着急.瞧着吧
It's wicked fast and damn near impossible to see.
它飞得贼快.你都没法看清
What do I do with it?
我该做什么？
You catch it. Before the other team's Seeker.
抓到它.抢在对方之前
You catch this, the game's over.
不管哪方.只要抓到它.就是赢家
You catch this, Potter,
你一抓到它.波特…
and we win.
比赛就结束
One of a wizard's most rudimentary skills is levitation...
作为一个魔法师.其基本功之一就是飘浮升空.就是…
...or the ability to make objects fly.
拥有能力使物体…飞起来
Do you have your feathers?
你们都拿到羽毛了吗？
Good.
很好
Now, don't forget the nice wrist movement we've been practicing.
现在…别忘了我们一直在练的手腕动作
The swish and flick.
先一挥.再一抖
Everyone.
一起来
The swish and flick.
先一挥.再一抖
Good.
很好
Oh, and enunciate.
噢.咒语得念清楚
Wingardium Leviosa.
羽加迪姆 勒维奥萨
Off you go, then.
你们练吧
Wingardium Leviosa.
羽加迪姆 勒维奥萨
No, stop, stop, stop!
不.停..停…停…
You're going to take someone's eye out.
你要戳瞎别人的眼睛啦
Besides, you're saying it wrong.
再说.你也念错啦
It's Leviosa,
是勒维“奥”萨
not Leviosar.
不是勒维奥“萨”
You do it then, if you're so clever.Go on, go on.
你那么聪明,那你倒是试试看来啊…来啊
Wingardium Leviosa.
羽加迪姆 勒维奥萨
Well done!
好极了
See here, everyone, Miss Granger's done it!
大家看这儿.格兰杰小姐成功了
Splendid!
真太好了
Wingardium Leviosa.
羽加迪姆 勒维奥萨
Well done, dear.
干得好
I think we're going to need another feather over here.
我们这再需要一根羽毛.教授
"It's Leviosa,
是勒维“奥”萨
not Leviosar."
不是勒维奥“萨”
She's a nightmare, honestly!
真是个刺头.受不了
No wonder she hasn't got any friends.
怪不得她没什么朋友
I think she heard you.
我想她听见了
Where's Hermione?
赫敏在哪儿？
Parvati said she wouldn't come out of the bathroom.
帕瓦蒂·佩蒂尔说她在厕所不肯出来
She said that she'd been in there all afternoon, crying.
可能一下午都躲在里面.在哭
Troll in the dungeon!
巨怪！在地下教室
地下教室有巨怪
Thought you ought to know.
知道了吗
Silence!
肃…静！
Everyone will please not panic!
请大家别慌.都别慌
Now...
现在
...prefects will lead their house back to the dormitories.
级长们…把各学院的同学领回各自的宿舍
Teachers will follow me to the dungeons.
老师们和我一起去地下教室
Gryffindors, keep up, please,
格兰芬多的同学.都跟上
and stay alert.
保持警惕
How could a troll get in?
山怪怎么会进来的？
Not on its own. Trolls are really stupid.
山怪很笨
Probably people playing jokes.
不会自己进来的也许有人在开玩笑
What?
干嘛？
Hermione! She doesn't know.
去找赫敏.她还不知道
I think the troll's left the dungeon.
我想巨怪离开地下教室了
It's going into the girls' bathroom.
它去女厕所了
Hermione, move!
赫敏.快跑！
Help! Help!
救命！
Help!
救命啊！
Hey, pea brain!
嘿.大傻瓜！
Help!
救命！
Do something!
快想办法
What?
怎么办？
Anything!
怎么都行
Hurry up!
先一挥.再一抖！
Swish and flick.
先一挥.再一抖
Wingardium Leviosa.
羽加迪姆 勒维奥萨
Cool.
酷
Is it dead?
他是不是…死了？
I don't think so. Just knocked out.
我想没有.只是晕过去了
Troll boogers.
恶心得要命
Oh, my goodness!
噢…噢…我的天
Explain yourselves, both of you!
你们两最好解释一下
It's my fault, Professor McGonagall.
这事都怪我.麦格教授
Miss Granger?
格兰杰小姐？
I went looking for the troll.
是我去找巨怪的
I thought I could handle it.
我在书上读到过以为能对付它
But I was wrong.
可是我错了
If Harry and Ron hadn't come and found me,
如果不是哈利和罗恩来找我
I'd probably be dead.
我也许就死啦
Be that as it may,
就算是这样…
it was an extremely foolish thing to do.
这么做可真是愚蠢极了
I expected more rational behavior
本以为你做事比别人更有头脑
and am very disappointed in you.
可你却让我极为失望.格兰杰小姐
Five points will be taken from Gryffindor...
格兰芬多将被扣去五分
...for your serious lack of judgment.
因为你做事严重缺乏判断
As for you two gentlemen...
至于你们两位先生…
...I just hope you realize how fortunate you are.
我希望你们知道自己有多幸运
Not many first-year students could take on a troll...
一年级新生能勇斗山中巨怪
...and live to tell the tale.
还保住性命.这事可不多见
Five points...
加五分…
...will be awarded to each of you...
你们两每人加五分
...for sheer dumb luck.
只因为你们太走运
Perhaps you ought to go.
你们快走吧
It might wake up.
它可…它可没死
Good of you to get us out of trouble
没想到惹出这样的麻烦吧？
We did save her life.
提醒你！我们确实救了她的命！
She might not have needed saving if you hadn't insulted her.
提醒你！不是你惹恼了她.她根本就不需要你去救！
What are friends for?
朋友是用来干啥的？
Take a bit of toast, mate. Go on.
吃点吐司吧.快吃
Ron's right.
罗恩说得对
You'll need your strength today.
待会儿你得大干一场啊
I'm not hungry.
可我不饿
Good luck today, Potter.
祝你今天好运.波特
You've proven yourself against a troll.
既然你连巨怪都能对付得了
A game of Quidditch should be easy work.
那么小小的魁地奇就是小菜一碟啦
Even if it is against Slytherin.
即使对手是…斯莱特林
That explains the blood.
难怪他会流血
Blood?
流血？
Last night, I'm guessing Snape let
听着.我猜想.昨晚斯内普…
the troll in as a diversion...
把巨怪放进来做牵制
...so he could get past that dog.
那样他就能设法通过三头犬
But he got bit,
可结果他却被咬伤
that's why he's limping.
所以他瘸了腿
But why would anyone go near that dog?
他干嘛要通过三头犬呢？
At Gringotts, Hagrid took
那天.海格从古灵阁金库里
something out of the vault.
取出一件东西
Said it was Hogwarts business, very secret.
他说事关霍格沃茨.是绝密
You're saying...
那你是说…
That's what the dog's guarding.
那狗在看守那东西
That's what Snape wants.
斯内普想得到它
Bit early for mail, isn't it?
一大早就来邮件
But I never get mail.
我…从没邮件
Let's open it.
先打开再说
It's a broomstick.
是一把扫帚
That's not just a broomstick,
它可不是普通的扫帚.哈利
it's a Nimbus 2000!
它可是光轮2000
But who...
是谁…
Scared, Harry?
怕吗.哈利？
A little.
有点
It's all right.
没关系
I felt the same way before my first game.
我第一次出场也这样
What happened?
后来呢？
I don't really remember.
记不清啦
I took a Bludger to the head two minutes in.
一上场就被游走球打昏
Woke up in hospital a week later.
在医院躺了一星期
Welcome to Hogwarts' first
哈罗.这是霍格沃茨本季
Quidditch game of the season.
首场魁地奇比赛
Today's game, Slytherin versus Gryffindor!
今天的比赛是斯莱特林队对战格兰芬多队
Gryffindor!
格兰芬多！
The players take their positions...
双方队员已经各就各位
...as Madam Hooch steps onto the field to begin the game!
现在霍琦夫人正步入赛场.比赛即将开始
Now, I want a nice, clean game...
我希望双方能赛出水平
...from all of you!
赛出风格
The Bludgers are up, followed by the Golden Snitch.
游走球升空.接着是金色飞贼
Remember, the Snitch is worth 150 points.
记住.金色飞贼的分值为150分
The Seeker who catches the Snitch ends the game.
哪一方得到金色飞贼.比赛就结束
The Quaffle is released
鬼飞球被抛出
and the game begins!
比赛开始！
Angelina Johnson scores!
安吉利娜·约翰逊得分
Ten points for Gryffindor!
格兰芬多赢得10分
Yes!
好球！
Well done!
漂亮！
Slytherin takes the Quaffle.
现在.斯莱特林队抢到鬼飞球
Bletchley passes to Captain Marcus Flint.
德里安传给队长弗林特
Yes!
好！
Another 10 points to Gryffindor!
现在格兰芬多队又得10分
Oh, Yeah!
噢.太棒了…
Give me that!
给我
Take that side!
去那边
What's going on with Harry's broomstick?
哈利的扫帚怎么会这样？
It's Snape. He's jinxing the broom!
斯内普.他在念咒语
Jinxing the broom? What do we do?
他在念咒语？我们怎么办？
Leave it to me.
瞧我的
Come on, Hermione!
快点啊.赫敏
Lacarnum Inflamarae.
拉卡隆依佛摩瑞
Fire!
火
You're on fire!
你着火了
Go, go, go, go!
加油…
Looks like he's gonna be sick.
看来他要吐了
He's got the Snitch!
他抓到了飞贼
Harry Potter receives 150 points for catching the Snitch!
哈利·波特抓到了金色飞贼 获得150分
Gryffindor wins!
格兰芬多获胜！
Oh, No!
不会吧
Yeah!
耶！
Gryffindor! Gryffindor!
格兰芬多！格兰芬多！
Nonsense!
尽胡扯
Why would Snape put a curse on Harry's broom?
斯内普干嘛给哈利的扫帚念咒？
Who knows?
谁知道？
Why was he trying to get past that three-headed dog?
万圣节前夜…他干嘛要通过三头犬？
Who told you about Fluffy?
谁跟你说过毛毛？
Fluffy?
毛毛？
That thing has a name?
那怪物还有名字？
Of course he has a name. He's mine.
当然有名字.他是我的
I bought him off an Irishman.
是我去年在酒馆向一个爱尔兰人买的
I lent him to Dumbledore to guard...
后来借给邓布利多去看守…
Shouldn't have said that.
不能说.别再问了
No more questions! That's top-secret.
别再问任何问题.这可是最高机密
But whatever Fluffy's guarding, Snape's trying to steal it.
不管是什么东西.反正斯内普想要偷
Codswallop.
别胡说八道
Professor Snape is a Hogwarts teacher.
斯内普教授是霍格沃茨的老师
Teacher or not,
不管他是不是老师
I know a spell when I see one.
他就是在念咒
I've read all about them.
我知道.我在书上读过
You've got to keep eye contact,
念咒时紧盯目标
and Snape wasn't blinking.
斯内普眼睛连眨都不眨
Exactly.
千真万确
Now, you listen to me, all three of you.
你们都听着.给我听好
You're meddling in things that ought not to be meddled in.
你们在管那些不应该管的事
It's dangerous.
那很危险
What that dog is guarding is
那条狗看守的东西…
between Dumbledore and Nicholas Flamel.
仅限于邓布利多教授和尼可·勒梅
Nicholas Flamel?
尼可·勒梅？(著名炼金术士.最后一块魔法石拥有者)
I shouldn't have said that.
我…不该说的
I should not have said that.
我…真不该说漏嘴的,我真不该说
Nicholas Flamel.
尼可·勒梅
Who's Nicholas Flamel?
谁是尼可·勒梅？
I don't know.
不知道
Merry Christmas
圣诞快乐
Ring the Hogwart bell
敲响霍格沃茨的钟
Knight to E-5.
马走到一五
Queen to E-5.
后走到一五
That's totally barbaric!
这简直太野蛮啦
That's wizard's chess.
这是魔法师棋
I see you've packed.
行李收拾好了？
I see you haven't.
你可还没收拾
Change of plans. My parents
改变计划了.我爸爸妈妈…
went to Romania to visit my brother Charlie.
决定去罗马尼亚.去看我哥哥查理
He's studying dragons there.
他在那儿研究龙
Good. You can help Harry.
很好.你可以帮哈利了
He's going to the library to look up Nicholas Flamel.
他要去图书馆看看 找有关尼可·勒梅的资料
We've looked a hundred times!
我们已经找过一百遍了
Not in the restricted section.
可从没去禁区找过
Happy Christmas.
圣诞快乐
I think we've had a bad influence on her.
看来跟着我们连她也学坏了
Harry, wake up!
哈利.快醒醒！
Come on, Harry, wake up!
快.哈利.醒醒！
Happy Christmas, Harry.
圣诞快乐.哈利
Happy Christmas, Ron.
圣诞快乐.罗恩
What are you wearing?
你穿着新毛衣？
Oh, my mum made it.
噢…是我妈织的
Looks like you've got one too.
好像你也有一件
I've got presents?
我…我有礼物？
Yeah.
对
There they are.
在这儿呢
"Your father left this in my possession before he died.
你父亲临死前把这留下交给我
It is time it was returned to you.
现在该把它该还给你了
Use it well."
好好使用
What is it?
是什么？
Some kind of cloak.
像是一件斗篷
Well, let's see, then. Put it on.
好哇.那就穿上试试
My body's gone!
身体不见了
I know what that is. That's an invisibility cloak!
我知道这是什么.这是一件隐形斗篷
I'm invisible?
我隐形了啦？
They're really rare.
这真稀罕
I wonder who gave it to you.
是谁送给你的？
There was no name.
没有署名
It just said,
只是写了…
"Use it well."
好好使用
（禁书区）
Famous Fire-Eaters.
“著名的食火者”
Fifteenth-Century Fiends.
“十五世纪的恶魔”.勒梅…
Flamel. Nicholas Flamel.
尼可·勒梅
Where are you?
你在那儿？
Who's there?
谁在哪儿？
I know you're in there.
我知道你在里面
You can't hide.
你躲不了
Who is it?
是谁呀？
Show yourself.
快给我出来
Severus, I...
斯内普.我…
You don't want me as your enemy, Quirrell.
你可别把我当成你的敌人.奇洛
I don't know what you mean.
你干嘛找我
You know perfectly well what I mean.
你心里很清楚
We'll have another little chat soon.
我们改天再聊
When you've had time to decide where your loyalties lie.
等你有空决定好了该忠于谁我们再聊聊
Professors.
喔.两位教授
I found this in the restricted section.
瞧这个.我在禁区发现的
It's still hot.
还热着呢
That means there's a student out of bed.
一定有个学生溜下了床
Mum?
妈妈？
Dad?
爸爸？
Ron, you've really gotta see this!
罗恩.快过去看看.一定要去看
Ron, you've gotta see this!
罗恩
Ron, come on, get out of bed!
罗恩.行了.快点起床吧
Why?
干嘛？
There's something you've got to see!
你一定要跟我去看看.快跟我去
Come on! Come!
快点.快
Come look, it's my parents!
快来看.是我的父母
I only see us.
只有我们两个
Look in properly. Go on, stand there.
换个角度.站到这儿来
There. You see them, don't you?
好了.看见他们了吧？
That's me! Only I'm head boy.
那是我.我成了男学生会主席
And I'm holding the Quidditch Cup.
我抱着魁地奇杯
And bloody hell! I'm Quidditch captain too!
真是天大的美事儿.我还成了魁地奇队长
I look good.
我真神气
Harry, do you think this mirror shows the future?
哈利.这镜子 能显示未来的事？
How can it?
怎么可能？
Both my parents are dead.
我的父母都死了
Do you like yours, Ron?
喜欢你的那份吗.罗恩？
Ron?
罗恩
l'll be right back.
我马上回来
Wanna play chess
我们下棋吧
No.
不
Wanna go and visit Hagrid?
我们去海格那里？
No.
不
l know what you're thinking, but don't.
哈利.我知道你在想什么…
There's something not right about that mirror.
别去了.那个镜子有问题!
Back again, Harry?
你又来了.哈利？
I see that you, like many before you...
依我看.你跟许多人一样
...have discovered the delights of the Mirror of Erised.
发现了厄里斯魔镜带来的无穷乐趣
I trust by now you realize what it does.
我深信.你现在已经知道了它的魔力啦
Let me give you a clue.
我给你个提示
The happiest man on earth...
世界上最幸福的人
...would look in the mirror and see only himself...
在照镜子时看见的就是他自己
...exactly as he is.
自己本身的模样
So then, it shows us what we want.
它能让我们看到想要的东西？
Whatever we want.
无论是什么？
Yes.
对
And no.
又不对
It shows us nothing more or less...
它让我们看到的只是…
...than the deepest and most desperate desires of our hearts.
藏在我们内心深处的最迫切最强烈的欲望
Now you, Harry, who have never known your family...
而你.哈利.从没见过你父母
...you see them standing beside you.
所以你就看见他们站在你身旁
But remember this, Harry.
可你记住.哈利
This mirror gives us neither knowledge or truth.
这面镜子…没法给我们知识和真理
Men have wasted away in front of it.
人们在它面前虚度时光
Even gone mad.
甚至发疯
That is why tomorrow, it will be moved to a new home.
所以呢.明天就把这镜子搬走
And I must ask you...
我必须奉劝你…
...not to go looking for it again.
以后别再煞费苦心地去找它了
It does not do to dwell on dreams...
如果沉迷于梦想而忘记了生活
...and forget to live.
对你并没有好处
Hi, Hedwig.
你好.海德薇
Look at you, playing with your cards. Pathetic!
看看你.安排好你的课程（复习）.别老指望别人！
We've got final exams soon.
我们来做做即将到来的测验吧
l'm ready. Ask me any question.
我准备好了.可以问任何问题
What are the ingredients in a Forgetfulness Potion?
是吗？遗忘魔药里最基础的三种剂量是什么？
l forgot.
过
What do you plan to do if it's in the exam?
如果期末考试砸锅了怎么办？
- Copy off you - No, you won't.
- 抄你的呗 - 你不会
Besides, we're to be given special quills with an Anti-Cheating Spell.
况且根据考试规定.我们会被给予一支特殊的鹅毛笔.带反作弊魔咒的！
That's insulting! lt's as if they don't trust us! Dumbledore again!
太让人气愤了.他们竟然不相信我们！ 邓布利多的游戏卡
Leg-Locker Curse?
锁腿咒？
Malfoy.
马尔福（干的）
You have got to start standing up to people.
你必须在别人面前站起来.纳威！
How? l can barely stand at all!
噢.我根本站不住…太难受了！
l'll do the countercurse!
让我来给你解咒
No, that's all l need! You to set my kneecaps on fire!
不.那正是我需要的.让你来决定我正出血的膝盖怎么样.不公平！
l don't appreciate the insinuation, Longbottom.
我还不稀得给你解咒呢！以你的处境来说.隆巴！
Besides, if anyone cared to notice...
况且.如果有人稍稍注意到的话
...my eyebrows have completely grown back!
我的眉毛已经完全长好了！
l found him!
我找到他了！
''Dumbledore is famous for defeating the dark wizard Grindelwald in 1945.''
邓布利多因以下几点而闻名天下…在1945年打败了黑巫师格林德沃；
For discovering dragon blood...and his alchemy work with Nicholas Flamel'' !
发现了龙血的十二种用途.与同伴尼可勒梅一起为练金术作出了贡献
l knew it was familiar. l read it on the train.
我曾经读到过这个名字 在那天的火车上
Follow me!
跟我来！
Wait! Where are you going?
嗨.等一等.你们去哪儿？
What about the countercurse?
先给我解咒好不好？
I had you looking in the wrong section.
是我害你们找错了地方
How could I be so stupid?
我的脑子怎么会这么笨呢？
I checked this out weeks ago for a bit of light reading.
几星期前我借这本书读着消遣
This is light?
这还叫消遣？
Of course! Here it is!
在这.这就对了
Nicholas Flamel is the only known maker of the Sorcerer's Stone.
尼可·勒梅是唯一人所共知的…魔法石制造者
The what?
什么石？
Honestly, don't you two read?
难道你们俩不看书吗？
"The Sorcerer's Stone is a legendary
魔法石是一种神奇的物质
substance with astonishing powers.
有惊人的魔力
It'll transform any metal into pure gold...
它能把任何金属变成黄金
...and produces the Elixir of Life
还能制造长生不老药
which will make the drinker immortal."
喝过的人能永生
Immortal?
能永生？
It means you'll never die.
死不了.你懂吗
I know what it means!
这意思我懂
"The only Stone currently in existence
在目前仅存一块魔法石
belongs to Mr. Nicholas Flamel...
属著名的炼金术士
...the noted alchemist
尼可·勒梅所有
who last year celebrated his 665th birthday."
去年他庆祝并度过了他的665岁生日
That's what Fluffy's guarding.
那就是毛毛看守的东西
That's what's under the trap door. The Sorcerer's Stone.
也就是仅存下来的那块魔法石
Don't wish to be rude,
对不起.别怪我失理
but I'm in no state to entertain.
今天我没空跟你们玩
We know about the Sorcerer's Stone.
我们知道魔法石了
We think Snape's trying to steal it.
斯内普想偷那魔法石
Are you still on about him?
你们到底在哪儿怀疑他？
We know he's after it.
我们知道他要魔法石
We don't know why.
可不知道为什么
Snape is one of the teachers protecting the Stone.
斯内普是保护魔法石的老师之一
He won't steal it. What?
他可不会偷的 什么？
You heard.
你没听见？
Come on, I'm a bit preoccupied today.
好了.行啦.我今天有事要忙
Wait a minute. "One of the teachers"?
他也在保护魔法石？
There are other things defending the Stone, aren't there?
当然啦.还有别的办法来保护它 对吗？
Spells, enchantments.
咒语呀、魔法呀
Right. Waste of bloody time, if you ask me.
没错.我看是多此一举
Ain't no one gonna get past Fluffy.
谁都过不了毛毛那一关.哼哼
Ain't a soul knows how, except for me and Dumbledore.
没人知道办法.除了我和邓布利多
I shouldn't have told you that.
嗯.我不能告诉他们
Hagrid, what exactly is that?
海格.这到底是什么？
That? It's...
这是条？呃…
I know what that is!
我知道这是什么
But, Hagrid, how did you get one?
可是海格.你怎么弄来的？
I won it. Off a stranger I met down at the pub.
赢来的.是从陌生人那儿赢来的
Seemed quite glad to be rid of it, as a matter of fact.
不知怎么.他好像巴不得输给我
Is that...
这是一条…
...a dragon?
一条龙吗？
That's not just a dragon. That's a Norwegian Ridgeback.
它不光是一条龙.而且是条挪威脊背龙
My brother works with these in Romania.
我哥哥在罗马尼亚就是研究龙的
Isn't he beautiful?
它很漂亮吧？
Oh, bless him. Look, he knows his mummy.
瞧着小家伙.把我当妈妈啦
Hello, Norbert.
哈罗.萝蔔
Norbert?
它叫萝蔔？
He's gotta have a name, don't he?
是呀.它总得有个名字吧
Don't you, Norbert?
对不对.萝蔔？
He'll have to be trained up a bit, of course.
当然.它还得受点训练
Who's that?
谁在那儿？
Malfoy.
马尔福
Oh, dear.
噢.天哪
Hagrid always wanted a dragon.
海格一直想养一条龙
Told me so the first time I met him.
第一次见到他他就说过
It's crazy.
真是荒谬
And worse, Malfoy knows.
更糟的是马尔福知道了
I don't understand. Is that bad?
知道又怎么样.很糟吗？
It's bad.
糟透了
Good evening.
晚上好
Nothing, I repeat, nothing...
绝不…我重复.绝不行
...gives a student the right to walk about at night.
学生绝不可以夜间在校园擅自走动
Therefore, as punishment for your actions,
因此对你们的行为要处罚
50 points will be taken.
将扣你们五十分
50?!
五十分？
Each.
每个人扣五十分
To ensure it doesn't happen again...
为确保今后不再犯
...all four of you will receive detention.
你们四人都得关禁闭
Excuse me, professor,
对不起.教授
perhaps I heard you wrong.
也许我听错了
I thought you said the four of us.
你是说我们“四个人”？
No, you heard me correctly.
你没有听错.马尔福先生
Honorable as your intentions were,
尽管你的用意是好的
you too were out of bed after hours.
可你也违反校规夜间擅自走动
You will join your classmates in detention.
你得跟你的同学一起关禁闭
A pity they let the old punishments die.
可惜不再用老式的办法处罚啦
Was a time detention found you
以前关禁闭的时候
hanging by your thumbs in the dungeons.
得拴住大拇指吊在地下室里
God, I miss the screaming.
真想念那些尖叫声
You'll be serving detention with Hagrid tonight.
今天晚上关禁闭.你们得跟着海格
He's got a little job to do inside the Dark Forest.
他有点小事要办你们得跟他一起去禁林
A sorry lot, this, Hagrid.
一帮捣蛋鬼.海格
Good God,
噢.天哪
you're not still on about that bloody dragon, are you?
你该不会还在为那条龙生气吧？
Norbert's gone.
萝蔔走了
Dumbledore sent him off to Romania to live in a colony.
邓布利多送它去罗马尼亚过群居生活
That's good,
这可是好事呀？
isn't it? He's with his own kind.
和它的同类在一起
What if he don't like Romania?
可要是它不喜欢罗马尼亚呢？
What if the other dragons are mean to him?
要是其他的龙欺负它呢？
He's only a baby.
它毕竟还是个小宝宝
For God's sake, pull yourself together.
我说行了.你也得振作点 别伤心啦
You're going into the Forest.
一会儿还得去禁林呢
Got to have your wits about you.
你得多用点心才行
The Forest? I thought that was a joke.
去禁林？是在开玩笑吧
We can't go in there.
不能去那儿
Students aren't allowed.
那儿禁止学生去
And there are...
那儿还有…
...werewolves.
还有狼人
There's more than werewolves in those trees.
那林子里有的不光是狼人
You can be sure of that.
这是肯定的
Nighty-night.
晚安啦
Right.
好吧
Let's go.
我们走
Hagrid, what is that?
哇.海格.那是什么？
What we're here for.
就是为这来的
See that?
看见吗？
That's unicorn blood, that is.
这是独角兽的血
I found one dead a few weeks ago.
几星期前有一条死了
Now,
现在…
this one's been hurt bad by something.
这头看来伤得也不轻
So,
所以…
it's our job to go
我们的任务是…
and find the poor beast.
去找那可怜的家伙
Ron, Hermione, come with me.
罗恩、赫敏.你们跟着我
Ok
好吧
And, Harry, you'll go with Malfoy.
哈利.你跟马尔福走
Okay. Then I get Fang.
行了.可我要牙牙
Fine.
好哇
Just so you know, he's a bloody coward.
可我提醒你.它是个胆小鬼
Wait till my father hears about this.
我爸要是知道了准有好戏看
This is servant's stuff.
喔.咱干佣人的活
If I didn't know better,
要是我没猜错的话.德拉科
I'd say you were scared.
我看你是害怕了
I'm not scared, Potter.
才不怕呢.波特
Do you hear that?
听见没？
Come on, Fang.
走吧.牙牙
Scared!
谁怕呀！
What is it, Fang?
是什么.牙牙？
help...help....
救命…救命！
Harry Potter, you must leave.
哈利·波特.你必须离开这儿
You are known to many creatures here.
这儿很多动物都知道
The Forest is not safe at this time.
这会儿的禁林可不安全
Especially for you.
尤其是对你
What was that thing you saved me from?
刚才你救了我.可那是什么？
A monstrous creature.
那是一个怪物
It is a terrible crime to slay a unicorn.
屠杀独角兽就是犯下重罪
Drinking its blood will keep you alive
喝了独角兽的血能延续你的生命
even if you are an inch from death.
哪怕你在濒临死亡的时候
But at a terrible price.
可这代价很惨重
For you have slain something so pure...
如果你屠杀这么纯洁的生命
...that the moment the blood touches your lips,
那么从它的血碰沾上你嘴唇的 那一刻起
you will have a half-life.
你就半生半死啦
A cursed life.
余生受到诅咒
Who would choose such a life?
这么活着的人是谁？
Can you think of no one?
难道你想不出？
Do you mean to say that
那你是说…
that thing that killed the unicorn...
杀了独角兽的那个东西
...that was drinking its blood,
也就是喝了它血的
that was Voldemort?
可怕的佛地魔？
Do you know what is hidden
你知道此时此刻
in the school at this very moment?
学校里藏着什么东西.波特先生？
The Sorcerer's Stone.
藏着魔法石
Harry!
哈利！
Hello there, Firenze.
你好.费伦泽
See you've met our young Mr. Potter.
看来你见过小波特了
You all right there, Harry?
没事吧.哈利？
Harry Potter,
哈利·波特…
this is where I leave you.
我就陪到这儿
You're safe now.
你安全了
Good luck.
祝你好运
You mean, You-Know-Who is out there
你是说那个神秘人现在就在那儿？
right now in the Forest?
他就在禁林里吗？
But he's weak.
他很虚弱
He's living for unicorn.
靠独角兽的血活命
Don't you see?
还不明白？
We had it wrong.
我们错了
Snape doesn't want the Stone for himself.
斯内普不是为他自己
He wants it for Voldemort.
他偷石头是为了佛地魔
With the Elixir of Life,
有长生不老药
Voldemort will be strong again.
给佛地魔恢复元气
He'll come back.
让他卷土重来
But if he comes back...
如果他卷土重来…
...you don't think he'll try to kill you, do you?
你以为他会不会想…会不会想杀你？
If he'd had the chance, he might have tried tonight.
他没机会.不然今天晚上就能杀我
And to think I've been worrying about my Potions final.
可我却在为魔药学期末考担心呢
Hang on a minute. We're forgetting one thing.
都好好想想.有一点我们都忘了
Who's the one wizard Voldemort always feared?
佛地魔一向都害怕的那个魔法师是谁呢？
Dumbledore.
邓布利多
As long as Dumbledore is around, Harry, you're safe.
只要有邓布利多在.哈利.你就安全
As long as Dumbledore is around,
只要有邓布利多在
you can't be touched.
佛地魔就不敢动
I'd heard Hogwarts' final exams were frightful,
以前一直听说霍格沃茨期末考试很可怕
but I found that enjoyable.
我倒觉得挺好玩的
Speak for yourself.
我可没有这种感觉
All right there, Harry?
怎么啦.哈利？
My scar.
我的疤
It keeps burning.
像火在烧
It's happened before.
以前也有过
Not like this.
不像这次
You should see the nurse.
去找个护士看看
I think it's a warning.
这是警告
It means danger's coming.
意味着危险来临
- Of course! - What is it?
- 呵…这就对了 - 怎么啦？
Isn't it odd that what Hagrid wants
你们不觉得奇怪吗？
more than anything is a dragon...
海格当时一心想要一条龙
...and a stranger just happens to have one?
这么巧就碰上了有龙的陌生人
How many people wander around with dragon eggs?
想想看.谁会在兜里揣着龙蛋 到处逛呢？
Why didn't I see it before?
为什么以前没想到呢？
Who gave you the egg?
海格.龙蛋是谁给你的？
What did he look like?
那人长什么样？
I never saw his face.
不知道.没看清他的脸
He kept his hood up.
他戴着头帽
You and this stranger must have taliked.
那陌生人.你们一定谈过话吧？
He wanted to know what sort of creatures I looked after.
他想知道我以前照料过哪些动物
I said, "After Fluffy,
我说连毛毛我都照料过
a dragon's gonna be no problem."
一条龙更不成问题啦
Was he interested in Fluffy?
他对毛毛感兴趣吗？
Of course he was interested.
喔.他当然对毛毛感兴趣
How often do you come across a three-headed dog?
即使是魔法师也难得有机会见到三头犬的
But I told him,
当时我跟他说…
"The trick with any beast is to know
对付野兽的窍门就是
how to calm him."
知道怎么让它安静
Take Fluffy, for example.
就比如说毛毛吧
Play him music and he falls straight to sleep.
给它来点音乐就睡着了
I shouldn't have told you that.
噢.不该告诉你们的
Where are you going?
你们去哪儿？你们…
We have to see Dumbledore.
我们要见邓布利多教授
Immediately!
这会儿都得见！
I'm afraid he's not here.
恐怕邓布利多教授不在这儿
He received an urgent owl from the Ministry of Magic and left.
他收到猫头鹰从魔法部送来的急件立刻动身赶往伦敦去了
He's gone?
他走了？
But this is important!
这件事很重要
This is about the Sorcerer's Stone!
是有关魔法石的事
- How do you know... - Someone's going to try and steal it.
- 你们知道… - 有人想要把它偷走
I don't know how you know,
我不知道你们会怎么知道魔法石的
but I assure you it is well protected.
可你们放心.它受严密保护
Now would you go back to your dormitories?
现在回你们的宿舍去吧
Quietly.
别声张
That was no stranger Hagrid met.
海格碰到的绝对不是陌生人
It was Snape.
而是斯内普
Which means he knows how to get past Fluffy.
这就是说他知道怎么通过毛毛
And with Dumbledore gone...
邓布利多偏偏不在…
Good afternoon.
下午好
What would three young Gryffindors...
像你们三位这样的格兰芬多年轻人
...be doing inside on a day like this?
怎么甘愿呆在屋里呢.外面天气多好？
- We were just... - You ought to be careful.
- 我们只是… - 得小心点
People will think you're...
人们会以为…
...up to something.
你们在干坏事
Now what do we do?
现在怎么办？
We go down the trap door.
去活板门下
Tonight.
今晚
Trevor.
吹宝…吹宝
Trevor,
go! You shouldn't be here!
走.你不该来这儿
Neither should you.
你们也不该来这儿
You're sneaking out again, aren't you?
你们又偷溜出来了.对吗？
Neville, listen. We were...
纳威.你听着.我们…
- We were... - No, I won't let you!
- 我们在… - 不许去
You'll get Gryffindor into trouble again.
别给格兰芬多惹麻烦
I'll fight you.
我…我跟你们拼了
Neville, I'm really sorry about this.
纳威.委屈你了.真对不起你
Petrificus Totalus.
变成…石头人
You're a little scary sometimes,
你有时候真有点吓人
you know that?
知道吗？
Brilliant, but scary.
很高明.但很可怕
Let's go.
我们走
- Sorry. - It's for your own good, you know.
- 对不起 - 对不起.这可是为你好
You stood on my foot!
啊.你踩我脚了
Sorry.
对不起
Alohomora.
[开门咒] 阿拉霍魔拉
Wait a minute. He's...
等一下.它在…
...snoring.
打呼噜
Snape's already been here.
斯内普已经来过了
He's put a spell on the harp.
他对竖琴念了魔咒
It's got horrible breath.
噢.这口臭可真熏人
We have to move its paw.
把它的爪子挪开
What?
什么？
Come on!
来吧！
Okay. Push.
好呐.一起推
I'll go first.
我头一个进去
Don't follow until I give you a sign.
等我给信号.你们再下来
If something bad happens, get yourselves out.
如果出了什么意外你们就只管自己逃出去
Does it seem a bit quiet to you?
是不是有点…太安静了？
The harp.
竖琴
It's stopped playing.
它不演奏了
Jump!
跳下去！
跳！
Lucky this plant thing's here, really.
幸好有这些植物在这儿
Stop moving, both of you.
别乱动.都别动
This is Devil's Snare.
这是魔鬼网
You have to relax.
你们必须放松
If you don't, it will only kill you faster.
不放松你们就会死得更快
Kill us faster?
死得更快？
Oh, now I can relax!
噢.那我可真要放松啦
Hermione!
赫敏！
Now what are we gonna do?
现在我们怎么办？
Just relax!
你要放松
Hermione, where are you?
赫敏.你在哪儿？
Do what I say!
照我说的做
Trust me.
相信我
Ah! Harry!
啊…哈利！
Oh!
噢！
Are you okay?
你没事吧？
Yeah, I'm fine.
没事.我挺好
He's not relaxing, is he?
他一点都没放松？
Apparently not.
他没听你的
- We've gotta do something. - What?
- 我们得想办法 - 怎么办？
I remember reading something in Herbology.
我记得在草药学里读过
Devil's Snare, Devil's Snare.
救命.救我…
It's deadly fun...
说来真有趣
...but will sulk in the sun!
一见太阳往回收
That's it! It hates sunlight.
没错.恶魔网最讨厌阳光
Lumus Solem.
[荧光闪烁咒] 路摸思
Ron, you okay?
罗恩.没事吧？
Yeah.
没事
Lucky we didn't panic.
噢.幸好没有慌张
Lucky Hermione pays attention in Herbology.
幸好赫敏认真读过草药学
What is that?
什么声音？
I don't know.
不知道
Sounds like wings.
像翅膀煽动
Curious.
奇怪
I've never seen birds like these.
我没见过这样的鸟
They're not birds. They're keys.
这些不是鸟.是钥匙
And I'll bet one of them fits that door.
肯定有一把能打开那扇门
What's this all about?
这到底怎么回事？
I don't know.
我不知道
Strange.
奇怪
Alohomora!
[开门咒] 阿拉霍魔拉
Well, it was worth a try.
噢.我是想试试
What will we do?
噢.我们怎么办？
There must be a thousand keys.
这儿一定有上千把钥匙
We want a big, old-fashioned one.
找一把老式的大钥匙
Probably rusty.
只怕锈得像把手了
I see it! The one with the broken wing.
那儿.我看见啦 是往上的那个
What's wrong?
怎么啦.哈利？
It's too simple.
这也太简单了
Go on!
噢.快上.哈利
If Snape could catch it on that old broomstick,
如果斯内普骑着扫帚能抓到
you can.
那你也能
You're the youngest Seeker in a century.
你是百年最棒的找球手
This complicates things a bit.
这下可不简单了
Catch the key!
接住钥匙
Hurry up!
快点！
I don't like this.
我不喜欢这儿
I don't like this at all.
一点也不喜欢
Where are we?
这是哪儿？
A graveyard.
是墓地吗？
This is no graveyard.
怎么是墓地呢
It's a chessboard.
这是张棋盘
There's the door.
门在那儿
Now what do we do?
我们怎么过去？
It's obvious, isn't it?
这不明摆着？
We've got to play our way across the room.
得下棋才能走到门那儿
Harry,
好吧
you take the empty bishop's square.
哈利.你站在象那个空格
Hermione, you'll be the queen-side castle.
赫敏.你就去做后一车
As for me,
至于我嘛…
I'll be a knight.
上马做骑士
What happens now?
现在该干嘛？
Well, white moves first.
好吧.现在白方先走
And then...
然后…
...we play.
开战
Ron,
罗恩
you don't suppose this is going to be like...
我们这样下棋该不会是在下…
...real wizard's chess, do you?
真正的魔法师棋吧？
You there, D-5.
黑棋走D5
Yes, Hermione.
没错.赫敏
I think this is gonna be
我想你说得对极了
exactly like wizard's chess.
正是在下魔法师棋
Castle to E-4!
车走到E4
Pawn to C-3!
卒走C3
Wait a minute.
你们等一下
You understand right, Harry.
看来你懂了.哈利
Once I make my move,
我只要一走下一步
the queen will take me.
后就会吃了我
Then you're free to check the king.
这样你就能去将死王
No. Ron, no!
不！罗恩！不！
What is it?
怎么回事？
He's going to sacrifice himself.
他打算牺牲他自己
No, there must be another way!
不.这不行.一定有别的办法
Do you wanna stop Snape from getting that Stone or not?
你们还想不想阻止斯内普偷魔法石啦？
Harry, it's you that has to go on.I know it.
哈利.我很清楚该继续前进的是你
Not me. Not Hermione. You.
不是我.也不是赫敏.是你
Knight to H-3.
马走到H3
Check.
将军
Ron!
罗恩！
No, don't move!
不！别动
Don't forget, we're still playing.
别忘了棋还没下完
Checkmate.
你被将死了
Take care of Ron.
你照顾罗恩
Then go to the owlery.
然后去找猫头鹰
Send a message to Dumbledore.
给邓布利多送个信
Ron's right.
罗恩说得对
I have to go on.
我得继续
You'll be okay, Harry.
你能行.哈利
You're a great wizard.
你是优秀的
You really are.
魔法师
Not as good as you.
你比我强
Me? Books and cleverness.
我靠书本和小聪明
There are more important things.
有比这更重要的是
Friendship and bravery.
友谊和勇气
And, Harry, just be careful.
哈利.你多加小心
You?
是你？
No, it can't be.
不.这不可能
Snape, he was the...
斯内普…他才…他才是…
Yes, he does seem the type, doesn't he?
他确实看着像坏人
Next to him, who would suspect...
有他在.谁还会怀疑…
...poor, stuttering Professor Quirrell?
可…可…可…可怜的 奇…奇…奇…奇洛教授？
But that day, during the Quidditch match,
可…可那天魁地奇比赛的时候
Snape tried to kill me.
斯内普想要害死我
No, dear boy.
啊…不.孩子
I tried to kill you!
是我想害死你
If Snape's cloak hadn't caught fire and broken my eye contact...
相信我吧要不是斯内普的斗篷着了火挡住我的视线
...I would have succeeded.
我早就要了你的小命
Even with Snape muttering his countercurse.
就算斯内普再怎么念反咒也救不了你
Snape was trying to save me?
他念咒语是想要救我？
I knew you were a danger to me,
我一开始就知道你是个威胁
especially after Halloween.
尤其万圣节之后
Then you let the troll in!
是你放巨怪进来的？
Very good, Potter, yes.
没错.波特.你真行
Snape, unfortunately, wasn't fooled.
只可惜斯内普没有上当
While everyone ran about,
别的人在地下室内瞎忙活
he went to the third floor to head me off.
他却直奔三楼阻拦我
He, of course, never trusted me again.
当然啰.他再也不信我了
He rarely left me alone.
他不让我一个人呆着
But he doesn't understand.
可他并不明白
I'm never alone. Never.
我不是一个人
Now,
呃…
what does this mirror do?
这面镜子干什么用的？
I see what I desire.
我看见我的欲望
I see myself holding the Stone.
我看见我拿着魔法石
But how do I get it?
可我怎么得到？
Use the boy.
利用这孩子
Come here, Potter!
你过来.波特！
Now!
快！
Tell me,
告诉我…
what do you see?
你看见什么了？
What is it? What do you see?
快说.看见什么啦？
I'm shaking hands with Dumbledore.
我跟邓布利多在握手
I've won the house cup.
我赢得了学院杯
He lies.
他撒谎
Tell the truth!
给我说实话
What do you see?
看见什么了？
Let me speak to him.
我来跟他说
Master, you are not strong enough.
主人.你的体力还不够
I have strength enough for this.
我对付这件事体力足够啦
Harry Potter...
哈利·波特…
...we meet again.
我们又见面了
Voldemort.
佛…佛地魔
Yes.
正是
You see what I've become?
瞧我成什么啦？
See what I must do to survive?
瞧我为了活命必须做什么？
Live off another.
寄生在别人身上
A mere parasite.
这条寄生虫
Unicorn blood can sustain me...
独角兽的血能延续我生命
...but it cannot give me a body of my own.
可没法让我有自己的躯体
But there is something that can.
有一件东西能解决问题
Something that, conveniently enough,
这件东西现在近在咫尺
lies in your pocket.
就在你的口袋里
Stop him!
抓住他！
Don't be a fool.
别犯傻了
Why suffer an horrific death...when you can join me and live?
干嘛要忍受痛苦的惨死呢？你可以投靠我.留条命
Never!
休想！
Bravery.
有勇气
Your parents had it too
就像你的父母
Tell me,
告诉我
Harry...
哈利…
...would you like to see your mother and father again?
你还想再见到你的妈妈和爸爸吗？
Together...
你我合作…
...we can bring them back.
能让他们起死回生
All I ask is for something in return.
我所要只是一点回报
That's it, Harry.
仅此而已.哈利
There is no good and evil.
这世上并没有什么善、恶
There is only power...
只有夺得权利的
...and those too weak to seek it.
和那些无力谋取权力的人
Together, we'll do extraordinary things.
你我合作…可以干出一番惊天动地的事来
Just give me the Stone!
快把魔法石给我
You liar!
你这骗子
Kill him!
杀了他
What is this magic?
这是什么魔法？
Fool, get the Stone!
笨蛋！快去拿石头
（早日康复）
Good afternoon, Harry.
下午好.哈利
Tokens from your admirers?
哈.纪念品.是你的崇拜者送的？
Admirers?
崇拜者？
What happened in the dungeons between you and Professor
你和奇洛教授在地下教室的事 虽然是个保密
Quirrell is a secret.
却不径而走
So, naturally, the whole school knows.
所以整个学校自然也就全都知道了
I see that your friend Ronald has saved you the trouble...
啊.看来你那位朋友罗恩…
...of opening your Chocolate Frogs.
已经帮你省了麻烦.打开了巧克力蛙
Ron was here? Is he all right?
罗恩来过了？他没事吧？
What about Hermione?
赫敏怎么样？
Fine.
好
They're both just fine.
他们俩个都挺好
What happened to the Stone?
魔法石怎么样了？
Relax, dear boy.
别紧张.亲爱的
The Stone has been destroyed.
那石头被毁了
My friend Nicholas and I have had a little chat...
我和的朋友尼可和我商量了一下
...and agreed it was best all around.
都认为只有这么做最妥当
But then, Flamel, he'll die, won't he?
可这样的话尼可就会死啦？
He has enough Elixir to
他有足够的灵药.一直能活到
set his affairs in order.
料理完他自己的事
But yes,
你说得没错
he will die.
他的确会死
How is it I got the Stone, sir?
我怎么会得到魔法石的？
One minute I was staring in the mirror and...
先前.我还在照镜子不一会儿…
You see, only a person...
要知道？只有那种…
...who wanted to find the Stone, find it...
一心只想找到石头
...but not use it,
而又不利用它的人
would be able to get it.
才能最终得到它
That is one of my more brilliant ideas.
这件事整个过程都在我的计划之中
And between you and me,
你我很默契
that is saying something.
自始至终都很默契
Does that mean, with the Stone gone,
那么说现在石头没了…
that Voldemort can never come back?
佛地魔就不会回来啦？
I'm afraid...
呃…恐怕…
...there are ways in which he can return.
他有许多办法可以回来
do you know why...
你是不是知道…
...Professor Quirrell couldn't bear to have you touch him?
奇洛教授为什么禁不起你碰他？
It was because of your mother.
那是因为你母亲
She sacrificed herself for you.
为了你她牺牲了自己
And that kind of act leaves a mark.
这样的行为会留下了一个印记
No, this kind of mark cannot be seen.
不…不…这种印记是看不见的
It lives in your very skin.
和你的肌肤融为一体
What is it?
是什么？
Love, Harry. Love.
爱.哈利.是爱
Bertie Bott's Every Flavor Beans.
啊…多味豆？是比比多味豆哇
I was most unfortunate in my youth
我年轻那会儿…
to come across a vomit-flavored one.
吃过一颗呕吐口味的
And since then, I've lost my king for them.
真是倒霉透了 从那时候起我就对它没了好感
But I think I could be safe...
这回来颗太妃口味的
...with a nice toffee.
应该没问题
Alas!
哦…我的天哪
Earwax.
像耳屎
All right there, Ron?
还好吧.罗恩？
All right. You?
挺好.你呢？
All right.
还行
Hermione?
赫敏？
Never better.
再好没有了
（斯莱特林学院）
Another year gone.
又一学年结束了
And now, as I understand it,
现在又到时候啦…
the house cup needs awarding.
该颁发学院杯了
And the points stand thus:
各学院的得分如下…
In fourth place,
第四名…
Gryffindor with 312 points.
格兰芬多.总分312分
Third place,
第三名…
Hufflepuff with 352 points.
赫奇帕奇.总分352分
In second place...
位居第二的是…
...Ravenclaw with 426 points.
拉文克劳.他们所得的分数是426分
And in first place...
位居榜首的是…
...with 472 points,
总分472分的
Slytherin house.
斯莱特林学院
Nice one, mate.
Yes, well done, Slytherin.
很好.很好.好样的.斯莱特林
Well done.
好样的.斯莱特林
However,
不过…
recent events must be taken into account.
最近发生的事情也必须考虑进去
And I have a few last-minute points to award.
我还有一些最后的分数要奖励
To Miss Hermione Granger,
赫敏·格兰杰小姐
for the cool use of intellect...
当别人身陷险境
...while others were in grave peril...
她沉着巧妙地发挥才智
...50 points.
奖五十分
Good job.
干得好
Second, to Mr. Ronald Weasley,
第二项颁给罗恩·韦斯莱先生
for the best-played game of chess...
他展现了高超的棋艺
...that Hogwarts has seen these many years,
是霍格沃茨多年来最为出色的
50 points.
奖五十分
And third...
第三项…
...to Mr. Harry Potter...
颁给哈利·波特
...for pure nerve and outstanding courage...
表彰他的胆魄.和他那超凡的勇气
...I award Gryffindor house
我奖给格兰芬多学院…
60 points.
六十分
We're tied with Slytherin!
跟斯莱特林平了
Finally,
最后还有…
it takes a great deal of bravery to stand up to
对敌人坚持原则.奋力抵抗
your enemies...
需要勇气
...but a great deal more to stand up to your friends.
而对朋友坚持原则更需要勇气
I award 10 points...
我奖励十分…
...to Neville Longbottom.
给纳威·隆巴顿
Assuming that my calculations are correct...
如果我的计算准确无误的话
...I believe that a change of decoration is in order.
我想.这儿的装饰就需要改变了
Gryffindor wins the house cup.
格兰芬多赢得了学院杯
Yeah!
太好了
We win!
我们赢了
Hey, come on!
我们拿到了冠军
We win!
我们赢了
Come on, now. Hurry up, you'll be late.
好了.快点.要晚了
Train's leaving. Go on.
快点.快点.火车要开了
Come on, hurry up.
快点
Come on, Harry.
上车吧
One minute.
呃…你等等
Thought you were leaving without saying goodbye, did you?
还以为你不说再见就走了呢？
This is for you.
给你的
Thanks, Hagrid.
谢谢.海格
Go on. On with you. On with you now.
走吧.快上车.去吧.去吧
Oh, listen, Harry.
呃…听着.哈利…
If that dolt of a cousin of yours,
如果你那个笨蛋表兄
Dudley, gives you any grief...
达力再敢欺负你
...you could always threaten him...
你完全可以吓唬他…
...with a nice pair of ears to go with his tail.
这回除了尾巴.还会长两只猪耳朵
But we're not allowed to do magic
可…可是海格.出了霍格沃茨
away from Hogwarts. You know that.
就不许施魔法了.这你知道
I do.
知道
But your cousin don't, do he?
可你表兄不知道哇…嗯
Go.
回去吧
Feels strange to be going home, doesn't it?
回家的感觉很怪吧？
I'm not going home. Not really.
不是回家.不算是